<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Kian.WTF</title>
<link>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/</link>
<atom:link href="https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Kian Ghodoussi&#39;s Personal Website</description>
<generator>quarto-1.6.32</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>I’m Not a Good Enough Engineer to Code With LLMs</title>
  <link>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/ai_coding_thoughts.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>I experimented with LLM coding for a bit but quickly scaled back my usage to only niche use cases. I started by using it for data visualization and it one-shot converted my descriptions to the exact visuals in my mind. I then was dealing with a chunking edge case and it also solved it perfectly.</p>
<p>Only two days in and I found myself pulled towards a prompt every time I needed to think through a problem. It was addicting in a way that I’ve only ever experienced with gambling (with which I had a similarly brief foray). I soon found myself going back and forth, trying again and again to one-shot a more complex feature, going back and forth between the output and prompt specifications. I then closed the language model, spent 10 minutes of focused effort and built exactly what I needed.</p>
<p>Programming languages allow you to break down problems into multiple levels of hierarchy and abstraction. For me personally, even if I think through the approach, I only discover this structure after my first pass at a solution. I often tend to throw away my first solution and rewrite from scratch. Coding with LLMs for anything non-trivial hides this internal learning: I was instead operating at an input/output level.</p>
<p>If code is building blocks, LLMs can operate very well at the single block level. However, it’s not always obvious to me whether my current task is a single building block or a collection of them. Combined with the dopamine hit from successful one shot solutions and it was easy for me to turn the my slow and steady software engineering into a game of slots. Some huge wins but a net loss.</p>
<p>I’m sure a more discerning engineer could have a better intuition for the best time to hand off items to an LLM. But for me, I had to make a hard rule for myself that I won’t ever copy/paste LLM code to any of my work projects.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Random</category>
  <category>LLM</category>
  <guid>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/ai_coding_thoughts.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Reddit Blocked Me</title>
  <link>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/less_reddit.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>So I got blocked by reddit at a network level. Every so often and more and more I search for X reviews reddit. Despite all the astroturfing it’s a hard habbit to break.</p>
<p>Fortunately for me Reddit wanted to point me in a better direction. My phone with my primary browser are now blocked.</p>
<p>I really dont do anything too weird on my phone. I look up things every so often. I use safari with DuckDuckGo and some adblockers and icloud private relay.</p>
<p>I get similar treatment with my laptop. People who I work with or friends are stunned at how many Captchas I get. I might be missing something but it feels like we are moving in a direction in which if you make the minimum effort to preserve your online privacy, you are slowly being more and more blackballed.</p>
<p>Maybe this is the result of the damage inflicted bu AI scrapers in this gold rush bubble. Moving digital archives locally is on the todo list. Mildly concerned for the future of the internet.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Random</category>
  <guid>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/less_reddit.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLMs Replace Caulk with Cream Cheese</title>
  <link>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/llms_replace_caulk_with_cream_cheese.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Cream cheese is great on a bagel; it’s a pretty sorry replacement for caulk. They both fill holes in your wall just fine, but over time caulk hardens and cream cheese decays.</p>
<p>The hidden cost of LLMs is that their best applications displace the process that build the institutional knowledge necessary to keep companies afloat.</p>
<section id="two-examples" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="two-examples">Two Examples</h2>
<section id="end-to-end-customer-support-automation." class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="end-to-end-customer-support-automation.">End to end customer support automation.</h4>
<p>Let’s assume LLMs never hallucinate and follow instructions perfectly. They will follow the high level instructions and think reasonably within the bounds of your parameters. We are running a contact center for a telecom company and we want to deploy AI agents to automate our customer support. As an executive, this is a dream come true: I can simply describe what I want at a high level, have an engineer encode this into an agent, and I now have an army of customer support agents doing <strong>exactly what I told them to do.</strong></p>
<p>And that’s a problem.</p>
<p>I worked as a data scientist in the contact center industry for several years. I never once met an executive who actually understood what was happening on their phone calls. Contact centers function not because of their executive leadership, but in spite of it. Agents handle such a broad set of issues and queries that never propagate up to upper management. How would an AI agent handle credit locks? Arbitrary requests about whether NASCAR is included in their cable package? If Fiber is supported at their address?</p>
<p>All of these issues are solvable, but they require (1) the company to catch up with them as they appear and (2) the information to disseminate to the top level stakeholder. (1) loses the company money until (2) happens. And proper information dissemination is the largest unsolved in modern companies.</p>
<p>The cream cheese can fill the hole: costs go down, contact centers look fine. But now customers abuse the chatbot and so security costs go up. Revenue is dropping due to unexpected support and checkout issues. Customers churn to competitors. Observability and infrastructure costs go up. A functional organization held together by humans is now spending more money to “automate” their system.</p>
</section>
<section id="large-scale-text-data-analysis" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="large-scale-text-data-analysis">Large Scale Text Data Analysis</h4>
<p>The naive approach is to flood an LLM’s context window with as many documents as you can and ask it for an analysis or to answer a question of some kind. It’ll write up some plausible enough report. GPT can automate the first step of analysis: but the process of doing that first step as a human provides the framework for the actual meat of the analysis: the iterative process of learning, exploring, and digging.</p>
<p>There are ways you can improve the quality of the report. You can use the LLM to first organize excerpts and documents into categories, building a database to store and query these, feeding this structure recursively into an LLM. You can even put in some work to explore this structure yourself. But in this process you are again adding a layer of unreliability and obfuscation between you and the data, you are investing time into a process that is not building your domain knowledge. You are instead being steered not toward the crucial unknown unknown, but rather to the report that looks the most probable to the LLM.</p>
<p>The cream cheese fills the hole: LLMs are able to write reports that look human almost instantly. But analysts who were previously digging into the contents of data, accumulating domain knowledge are now spending their time prompting, tinkering, and churning out professionally written, insight-free reports.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="companies-need-caulk-to-harden" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="companies-need-caulk-to-harden">Companies Need Caulk to Harden</h2>
<p>My point here is not that LLMs are useless. Instead it’s that the applications that are the best fit for LLMs do not drive as much value as you expect because there is inherent value in the process of a human performing the task.</p>
<p>That value might be in the adaptability of a human contact center agent to handle the never ending long-tail of edge cases, or the willingness to break from guidelines when common sense dictates. It may be in the process of an analyst accumulating a broad swath of domain knowledge by manually digging through raw data that provides broader contexts to any insights and builds over time. It may be from a software engineer needing to actually read through the documentation of a core library in their production stack and eventually using that knowledge to make a tangential design decision.</p>
<p>Quantitative metrics will not capture the loss of these processes immediately. The cheese fills the hole and over the long term will decay. It’s much easier to just do the job correctly the first time.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>LLMs</category>
  <category>Opinion</category>
  <guid>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/llms_replace_caulk_with_cream_cheese.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hierarchical Mixture Model for Single Cell Sequencing I</title>
  <link>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/scrna-1/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>One of my favorite parts of my job is that I am able to spend 1 day per week focusing on applying our <a href="https://blog.sturdystatistics.com/posts/technology/">hierarchical mixture modeling technology</a> to genomic applications. I’ve been working closely with the <a href="https://www.holehouselab.com/team#yui_3_17_2_1_1763399224829_163">Ramiz Somjee</a> on applying our technology to scRNA sequencing data.</p>
<section id="tldr-why-im-excited" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="tldr-why-im-excited">TLDR: Why I’m Excited</h2>
<p>Current scRNA pipelines rely on a heuristic driven 2-step process. First some form of filtering+dimensionality reduction, followed by a clustering step, followed by either manual labeling of these clusters or a classification model to learn/apply annotation to this data.</p>
<p>Our technology can model this entire pipeline in as a single unified joint probabilty distribution with 3 branches. We have a topic branch that learns a probability distribution across genes for each topic, a cell branch that learns a probabilty distribution across topics for each cell, and a classification branch that learns regression weights for each cell’s topic distribution.</p>
<p>This is powerful because our topics are jointly modeling both the unsupervised co-occurance information along with any annotations provided. This structure enables not only <a href="https://sturdystatistics.com/features/#classification">robust, few-shot classification</a> but also extremely granular explainability.</p>
</section>
<section id="first-experiment" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="first-experiment">First Experiment</h2>
<p>We took an already annotated dataset that Ramiz was extremely familiar with to evaluate (1) whether our model was capable to learning the annotations and (2) whether the genes that comprised the predictive topics lined up with Ramiz’s extensive manual annotation process.</p>
<p>The model actually worked better than I could have hoped. We trained the model on 150 labels for 12 different cell types. We then evaluated the model on 2000 held out datapoints. Our model mislabelled only 3/2000 examples in the test set. We didn’t dig too deep into the model performance beyond that, since this was more just a validation experiement.</p>
<p>What I was really excited to dig into was the explanatory analysis. Our model uses a <a href="https://sturdystatistics.com/features/#error-tolerant">error-tolerant variant</a> of the sparsity-inducing <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1707.01694">Finish Horseshoe</a> prior that we call the Santa Barbara Horseshoe. This prior enables our model, with only a few examples, to confidently separate meaningful parameters from noisy ones.</p>
<p><img src="https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/scrna-1/Cone.png" class="img-fluid"> <img src="https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/scrna-1/Rod.png" class="img-fluid"> <img src="https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/scrna-1/BC.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<figcaption>
<strong>Figure 1:</strong> Predictive weight of all topics to the corresponding cell type prediction with the three closely related conical cell types. Any topic not shown was strongly consistent with 0 or no predictive importance. Notice that any topic that is strongly predictive for one classs is strongly negative for the other. Our model is able to split out three distinct topic groups within even closely related cell types because of our ability to jointly model topics with labels.
</figcaption>
<p>What’s really cool is now for any of the predictive topics, we can dig into the genes that comprise it:</p>
<section id="topic-49-predictive-of-rod" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="topic-49-predictive-of-rod">Topic 49: Predictive of Rod</h4>
<pre><code>['Sag', 'Gngt1', 'Rho', 'mt-Atp6', 'Pdc', 'Mir124-2hg', 'Prph2',
'mt-Co2', 'Unc119', 'Pde6g', 'Tma7', 'Rom1', 'Ubb', 'Nr2e3',
'Rpl26', 'Hsp90aa1', 'H3f3b', 'mt-Cytb', 'Gapdh', 'H3f3a',
'Rpgrip1', 'Pkm', 'Rp1', 'mt-Co3', 'Gnb1', 'mt-Co1', 'Ckb']</code></pre>
<p>These genes line up really exactly with Ramiz’s manual annotation. The difference was that this pipeline was fully automatic.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="next-steps" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="next-steps">Next Steps</h2>
<p>While I believe there is a lot of value to the explainble components of this model, we are going to focus on classification because it is much easier to quantitatively evaluate and can also solve a real pain point for the scRNA research community. I described the current painstaking process of annotating scRNA sequences that is extremely manual, heuristic, and time consuming. The reason for this current process is current classification methods do not generalize across experiments: batch effects throw off normal statistics based classification and clustering models.</p>
<p>Our model provides a number of avenues to handle batch effects. Our hope is that it works out of the box, but we also have hierarchical levers we can pull to factor batch effects directly into our model structure. We plan to take 35 annotated datasets of mouse eye scRNA sequences, train our model on one of them, and evaluate it’s performance on the other 34. Our model’s performancew ill determine the next steps from there, but I’m extremely excited and optimistic based on our initial set of results.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Genomics</category>
  <category>Bayesian Modeling</category>
  <guid>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/scrna-1/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>State of the AI Industry in a Screenshot</title>
  <link>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/state_of_ai_picture/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/state_of_ai_picture/state.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption>AI companies really make 180 degree shifts overnight.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Oct.&nbsp;2024 post goes into extended detail aobut how much work it is to build a RAG system, the competetive advantage in AI is not the LLM but being incredbly smart about what you feed into the context window.</p>
<p>Oct.&nbsp;2025 proclaims RAG is dead: just pass everything into the 2M token context window, let agents decide what to pass in.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nicolasbustamante.com/">Source</a>: Founder of a YC backed financial analysis company.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>LLMs</category>
  <category>Opinion</category>
  <guid>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/state_of_ai_picture/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Santa Barbara Burrito Week Prospective Itinerary</title>
  <link>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/santa_barbara_burrito_week_2025.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This is the set of restaurants for which I am the most personally excited about during <a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/">Santa Barbara burrito week</a>. This list factors in <em>variety, convenience, and excitement.</em> I will update this list as I eat. I may even get <em>crazy</em> and visit a place not on this list. I will keep you posted.</p>
<section id="kians-picks" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="kians-picks">Kian’s Picks</h2>
<table class="caption-top table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Restaurant</th>
<th>Description</th>
<th>Excitement</th>
<th>Hours</th>
<th>Bikeable</th>
<th>Vibe</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#poke">Poke House</a></td>
<td>poke burrito</td>
<td>10</td>
<td>11am-9pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>7.5</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#petra">Petra Cafe</a></td>
<td>falafel burrito</td>
<td>9</td>
<td>11am-11pm, X-monday</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>9</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#yona">Yona Redz</a></td>
<td>birria, fish</td>
<td>9</td>
<td>11am-9pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>6</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#goat">Goat Tree</a></td>
<td>lamb shwarma</td>
<td>9</td>
<td>7am-3pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#fish">SB Fish Market</a></td>
<td>shrimp</td>
<td>8.5</td>
<td>11am-7pm</td>
<td>N</td>
<td>7</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#fonda">Cafe la Fonda</a></td>
<td>veggie wet burrito</td>
<td>8.5</td>
<td>8am-4pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>8.5</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#agaves">Los Agaves</a></td>
<td>chicken, pastor, veggie</td>
<td>8.5</td>
<td>11am-9pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>8</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#arroyos">Los Arroyos</a></td>
<td>chicken burrito</td>
<td>8.5</td>
<td>11am-9pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>8</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#cocina">Corazon Cocina</a></td>
<td>paisa (pastor) burrito</td>
<td>8.5</td>
<td>11am-3pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>7</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#comedor">Comedor/little heart</a></td>
<td>breakfast burrito</td>
<td>8.5</td>
<td>8am-2pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>9</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#cat">Happy Cat Eats</a></td>
<td>mac &amp; cheese + breakfast</td>
<td>8</td>
<td>8am-630,730pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>?</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#alex">Little Alex</a></td>
<td>pancake burrito, birria</td>
<td>7.5</td>
<td>8am-11am, 9pm</td>
<td>~</td>
<td>6</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#rascal">Rascals</a></td>
<td>vegan chorizo</td>
<td>7.5</td>
<td>10am-1pm, 11am-2pm weekdays, 5pm-9pm all</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>?</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#yellow">Yellow Belly</a></td>
<td>carna asada+chorizo+wet</td>
<td>7</td>
<td>4pm-830pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>9</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#maiz">Maize Picante</a></td>
<td>veggie, carnitas, pastor</td>
<td>6</td>
<td>11am-10pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>6</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</section>
<section id="funky-features" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="funky-features">Funky Features</h2>
<table class="caption-top table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Restaurant</th>
<th>Description</th>
<th>Excitement</th>
<th>Hours</th>
<th>Bikeable</th>
<th>Vibe</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#poke">Poke House</a></td>
<td>poke burrito</td>
<td>10</td>
<td>11am-9pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>7.5</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#goat">Goat Tree</a></td>
<td>lamb shwarma</td>
<td>9</td>
<td>7am-3pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#petra">Petra Cafe</a></td>
<td>falafel burrito</td>
<td>9</td>
<td>11am-11pm, X-monday</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>9</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#fish">SB Fish Market</a></td>
<td>shrimp</td>
<td>8.5</td>
<td>11am-7pm</td>
<td>N</td>
<td>7</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#cat">Happy Cat Eats</a></td>
<td>mac &amp; cheese + breakfast</td>
<td>8</td>
<td>8am-630,730pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>?</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#alex">Little Alex</a></td>
<td>pancake burrito, birria</td>
<td>7.5</td>
<td>8am-11am, 9pm</td>
<td>~</td>
<td>6</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#rascal">Rascals</a></td>
<td>vegan chorizo</td>
<td>7.5</td>
<td>10am-1pm, 11am-2pm weekdays, 5pm-9pm all</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>?</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</section>
<section id="convenience-is-key" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="convenience-is-key">Convenience is Key</h2>
<table class="caption-top table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Restaurant</th>
<th>Description</th>
<th>Excitement</th>
<th>Hours</th>
<th>Bikeable</th>
<th>Vibe</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#agaves">Los Agaves</a></td>
<td>chicken, pastor, veggie</td>
<td>8.5</td>
<td>11am-9pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>8</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#yellow">Yellow Belly</a></td>
<td>carna asada+chorizo+wet</td>
<td>7</td>
<td>4pm-830pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>9</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/09/17/roll-em-up-chow-em-down-its-burrito-week-2025/#maiz">Maize Picante</a></td>
<td>veggie, carnitas, pastor</td>
<td>6</td>
<td>11am-10pm</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>6</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Santa Barbara</category>
  <guid>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/santa_barbara_burrito_week_2025.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Santa Barbara Sandwich Week Prospective Itinerary</title>
  <link>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/santa_barbara_sandwich_week_2025.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This is the set of restaurants for which I am the most personally excited about during <a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/06/25/santa-barbaras-first-ever-sandwich-week">Santa Barbara sandwich week</a>. This list factors in <em>variety, convenience, and excitement.</em> I will update this list as I eat. I may even get <em>crazy</em> and visit a place not on this list. I will keep you posted.</p>
<section id="kians-itinerary" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="kians-itinerary">Kian’s Itinerary</h2>
<table class="caption-top table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Restaurant</th>
<th>Description</th>
<th>Excitement</th>
<th>Hours</th>
<th>Bikeable</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/06/25/santa-barbaras-first-ever-sandwich-week/#blackbird">Blackbird</a></td>
<td>Fried Chickem</td>
<td>9.5</td>
<td>Tue-Sat 5pm-</td>
<td>y</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/06/25/santa-barbaras-first-ever-sandwich-week/#poke">Poke House</a></td>
<td>Salmon Poke</td>
<td>9.5</td>
<td>11am - 9pm</td>
<td>y</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/06/25/santa-barbaras-first-ever-sandwich-week/#goat">Goat Tree</a></td>
<td>Egg Cheese Bacon</td>
<td>9</td>
<td>7am - 3pm</td>
<td>y</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/06/25/santa-barbaras-first-ever-sandwich-week/#white">White Caps</a></td>
<td>Brisket dip + tomato</td>
<td>9</td>
<td>8am - 1pm M-F</td>
<td>n</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/06/25/santa-barbaras-first-ever-sandwich-week/#connection">SB Food Connection</a></td>
<td>Chicken Pesto Pluma</td>
<td>8.5</td>
<td>11am - 8m (10pm fri-sun)</td>
<td>y</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/06/25/santa-barbaras-first-ever-sandwich-week/#dutch">Dutch Gardens</a></td>
<td>BLT</td>
<td>8</td>
<td>We - Sun 11am - 3pm</td>
<td>y</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/06/25/santa-barbaras-first-ever-sandwich-week/#petra">Petra Cafe</a></td>
<td>Chicken Schwarma</td>
<td>8</td>
<td>12pm - 11pm</td>
<td>y</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/06/25/santa-barbaras-first-ever-sandwich-week/#fish">SB Fish Market</a></td>
<td>Tuna Salad</td>
<td>8</td>
<td>9am - 630pm</td>
<td>n</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/06/25/santa-barbaras-first-ever-sandwich-week/#gala">Gala</a></td>
<td>Fried Chicken</td>
<td>8</td>
<td>Tue - Sat 4pm - 10pm</td>
<td>y</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</section>
<section id="johns-oak-park-additions" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="johns-oak-park-additions">John’s Oak Park Additions</h2>
<table class="caption-top table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Restaurant</th>
<th>Description</th>
<th>Excitement</th>
<th>Hours</th>
<th>Bikeable</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/06/25/santa-barbaras-first-ever-sandwich-week/#validation">Validation Ale</a></td>
<td>Gochujang Fried Chicken</td>
<td>6</td>
<td>M-Sa 1130am - 830pm</td>
<td>y</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td><a href="https://www.independent.com/2025/06/25/santa-barbaras-first-ever-sandwich-week/#yellow">Yellow Belly</a></td>
<td>Pulled Pork</td>
<td>6</td>
<td>M-Sa 4pm - 830pm</td>
<td>y</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Santa Barbara</category>
  <guid>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/santa_barbara_sandwich_week_2025.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SB Burger Week Tiers</title>
  <link>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/santa_barbara_burger_week_2024.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="sb-burger-week-tiers" class="level1">
<h1>SB Burger Week Tiers</h1>
<p>Tags Legend * V: upscale vibe * C: chilled vibe * +: Easy bike from oak park</p>
<section id="tier-1" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="tier-1">Tier 1</h2>
<table class="caption-top table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Restaruant</th>
<th>Tags</th>
<th>Hours</th>
<th>Notes</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Intermezza</td>
<td>V+</td>
<td>Tu-Sa: 5-9</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>La Paloma</td>
<td>V+</td>
<td>We-Su: 11:30-2:30, 5-630</td>
<td>wagyu</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>SBFC</td>
<td>C</td>
<td>M-Sa: 1-7</td>
<td>guac, 8</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Blackbird</td>
<td>V+</td>
<td>Tu-Sa: 5-10</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Gala</td>
<td>V+</td>
<td>Tu-Sa: 4-9</td>
<td>fried tomatos</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>SBFM</td>
<td>C</td>
<td>10-7</td>
<td>tuna 6 &amp; salmon 8.5</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="tier-1.5" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="tier-1.5">Tier 1.5</h2>
<table class="caption-top table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Restaruant</th>
<th>Tags</th>
<th>Hours</th>
<th>Notes</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Brewhouse</td>
<td>C+</td>
<td>M 4-9, 11-9</td>
<td>maybe only on monday?</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>mesa burger</td>
<td>C</td>
<td>11-8</td>
<td>surf and turf 9</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>finch and fork</td>
<td>V+</td>
<td>7-2, 4-9</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="tier-2" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="tier-2">Tier 2</h2>
<table class="caption-top table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Restaruant</th>
<th>Tags</th>
<th>Hours</th>
<th>Notes</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Creekside</td>
<td>C</td>
<td>MF 4-8, SaSu 11-8</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Little Bird</td>
<td>C+</td>
<td>11-8</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Sama Lama</td>
<td>C+</td>
<td>1130-9</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="something-new-tier-2" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="something-new-tier-2">Something New (Tier 2+)</h2>
<table class="caption-top table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Restaruant</th>
<th>Tags</th>
<th>Hours</th>
<th>Notes</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Petra Cafe</td>
<td>C+</td>
<td>Tu-Su: 12-11</td>
<td>Falafel 7.5</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Poke House</td>
<td>C+</td>
<td>11-9</td>
<td>Tuna Poke</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Daves Dogs</td>
<td>C</td>
<td>M-Sa: 11-11</td>
<td>fried chicken</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>SBFM</td>
<td>C</td>
<td>10-7</td>
<td>tuna &amp; salmon</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<hr>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Santa Barbara</category>
  <guid>https://sturdystatistics.com/blog/posts/santa_barbara_burger_week_2024.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
